Leslie Beal

supermomleslie@yahoo.com

469-714-7750

I am a dedicated Medical Assistant with more than 17 years of experience in fast-paced multi-physician practices. I have expert knowledge of medical terminology and I am highly trained with strong, efficient clinical abilities and a passionate commitment to first-rate patient care.

Skills

• Solid understanding of obstetric and gynecological care • Sound knowledge of patient care procedures • Substantial familiarity with patient privacy guidelines • Strong decision making abilities especially in fast-paced environments • Profound experience working in team settings • Great ability to prioritize and multi-task correctly ensuring an extremely efficient workflow.

Experience

August 2017- August 2018

Health Central Women's Care- *Medical Assistant*

- Worked efficiently in this busy multi-physician practice with the use of Centricity and DigiChart EMR systems.
- Assisted the physician with the daily ob/gyn clinical schedule.
- Took patient stats before the physician evaluated the patient.
- Assisted with all office procedures (all routine well woman exams, IUD insertions, Nexplanon insertions, colposcopies, LEEPs, endometrial biopsies, Endosee Hysteroscopy procedure, and all other needs requiring assistance).
- Performed Fetal Non-Stress Tests.
- Ordered and collected all requested lab testing.
- Administered required injections.
- Scheduled and ordered all requested imaging and mammograms.
- Scheduled L&D procedures (inductions, cytotech, c-sections, etc.)
- Provided preoperative and postoperative assistance with surgical cases, including preparation of surgery consents, orders, and any follow-up prescriptions needed.
- Answered patient questions and responded to follow-up calls and emails.
- Informed the patients of test results along with recommendations and instructions.
- Sent out prescriptions per the physician's orders.
- Cleaned, sterilized, and maintained daily routine sanitation of the work area and instruments used throughout the day.

• Ensured compliance with OB and Gyn quality care standards.

July 2016 - July 2017

Women's Health Alliance - *Medical Assistant*

- Worked efficiently in this busy multi-physician practice with the use of Centricity, Digi Chart, and eClinicalWorks EMR systems.
- Assisted the physician with the daily ob/gyn clinical schedule.
- Took the patient stats before the physician evaluated the patient.
- Assisted with all office procedures (all routine well woman exams, IUD insertions, Nexplanon insertions, colposcopies, endometrial biopsies, newborn circumcisions, and all other needs requiring assistance).
- Performed Fetal Non-Stress Tests.
- Ordered and collected all requested lab testing.
- Administered required injections.
- Scheduled and ordered all requested imaging and mammograms.
- Scheduled L&D procedures (inductions, cytotech, c-sections, etc.)
- Scheduled surgeries with the hospital, outpatient surgery centers, and in-office anesthesia group.
- Provided preoperative and postoperative assistance with surgical cases. Including preparation of surgery consents, orders, and any follow-up prescriptions needed.
- Completed FMLA and Short Term Disability forms.
- Answered patient questions and responded to follow-up calls and emails.
- Informed the patients of test results.
- Sent out prescriptions per the physician's orders.
- Cleaned, sterilized, and maintained daily routine sanitation of the work area and instruments used throughout the day.
- Ensured compliance with OB and Gyn quality care standards.

July 2009 - October 2015

Women's Health Specialist of Dallas - *Medical Assistant/Clinical Supervisor*

- Worked efficiently in this busy multi-physician practice with the use of Medical Manager,
 Centricity, Digi Chart, and Sage Intergy EMR systems.
- Assisted the physician with the daily ob/gyn clinical schedule.
- Took patient stats before the physician evaluated the patient.
- Assisted with all office procedures (all routine well woman exams, IUD insertions, Nexplanon insertions, LEEPs, colposcopies, endometrial biopsies, IUIs, and all other needs requiring assistance).
- Performed Fetal Non-Stress Tests.
- Ordered and collected all requested lab testing.
- Administered required injections.

- Scheduled and ordered all requested imaging and mammograms.
- Scheduled L&D procedures (inductions, cytotech/prepidil, c-sections, etc.).
- Scheduled surgeries with the hospital, outpatient surgery centers, and in-office anesthesia group.
- Answered patient questions and responded to follow-up calls and emails.
- Informed the patients of test results.
- Sent out prescriptions per the physician's orders.
- Cleaned, sterilized, and maintained daily routine sanitation of the work area and instruments used throughout the day.
- Ordered clinical office supplies, devices, and in-office medications, while ensuring that we maintained the lowest possible cost to the practice.
- I was promoted to Clinical Supervisor in September 2014.
- Managed and trained a clinical team of approximately 8.
- Ensured compliance with OB and Gyn quality care standards.

April 2001 - December 2008

Hussam H. Alibhai, M.D. - Medical Assistant

- Worked efficiently in this busy single physician practice with the use of Medical Manager and Centricity EMR systems.
- Assisted the physician with the daily ob/gyn clinical schedule.
- Took patient stats before the physician evaluated the patient.
- Assisted with all office procedures (all routine well woman exams, colposcopies, cryotherapy, and all other needs requiring assistance).
- Set up the ultrasound machine and assisted and/or performed ultrasounds.
- Performed Fetal Non-Stress Tests.
- Ordered and collected all requested lab testing.
- Administered required injections.
- Scheduled and ordered all requested imaging and mammograms.
- Scheduled L&D procedures (inductions, cytotech/prepidil, c-sections, etc.).
- Scheduled surgeries with the hospital, outpatient surgery centers.
- Provided preoperative and postoperative assistance with surgical cases.
- Completed FMLA and Short Term Disability forms.
- Answered patient questions and responded to follow-up calls and emails.
- Informed the patients of test results.
- Sent out prescriptions per the physician's orders.
- Cleaned, sterilized, and maintained daily routine sanitation of the work area and instruments used throughout the day.
- Ensured compliance with OB and Gyn quality care standards.

Education

${\bf Ar lington\ Medical\ Institute} - {\it Certified\ Medical\ Assistant}$

August 1995 - June 1999

Lancaster High School - High School Diploma

Certification

Current CCMA